William Sullivan

Austin, TX (512) 771-0978 https://billsullivan.name william@enkrates.com

PROFILE

I am an experienced software developer and technical leader with over fifteen years of professional experience. I previously studied Computer Science at The University of Texas at Austin. I currently work with Atlassian as a Senior Software Engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Marketing Engineering - Atlassian 2018-Present

I am a part of a small but growing team of engineers supporting the Atlassian Marketing department. Our team supports projects like ensuring GDPR compliance across our products and websites, customer personalization of our websites, and increasing speed and compliance of our marketing email process.

We use Java, Javascript, ReactJS and quite a few third-party integrations in our work (Salesforce Marketing Cloud and Pardot, for example). We follow a standard Agile Scrum process.

Team Lead, Ultra UI - Blackboard 2017-2018

I led a small team (5 developers, 1 QA) who were building out the new Blackboard Learn UI, Ultra. We worked with ReactJS, Typescript, Angular, Java, SASS, and tested the heck out of our code. We deployed to AWS via Jenkins CI. I split my time 50/50 between individual contributions to our codebase and management/scrum activities.

In my time at Blackboard, my team delivered significant updates to the Attendance, Assessments, and Analysis features of Learn.

Lead Software Developer, Writing Tools - Macmillan Learning 2016-2017

I led a small agile scrum team building out english composition web tools. We worked in two week sprints and build with NodeJs (Koa framework), Postgres, Docker, and ReactJS. We delivered a full web app that offered instructors full essay assignment management and students peer review features.

Senior Software Developer (Contract), Digital Customer API - Whole Foods Market 2016-2016 I was a part of the Whole Foods Digital Customer API team. I was responsible for building and supporting the API that supplies the customer and business data used in the Whole Foods and 365 store mobile apps and mobile websites. I supported a v2 API that was written in NodeJs and a v3 using PHP, Symfony2, PostgreSQL, and MongoDb.

Senior Software Developer (Contract), API Integrations - Macmillan Learning 2015-2016

This position involved stakeholder interaction, technical roadmap decision making, agile/Scrum leadership, and partner support in addition to software development. Our project was largely an integration between many distinct systems, so I was regularly in contact with technical and management team members with ownership of those systems.

My day to day development at Macmillan used PHP, MySQL, Javascript, and NodeJS.

Principal Developer - Big Shiba, LLC 2004-2014

Big Shiba LLC is a small company owned and operated by myself and my wife. I left full time work with Big Shiba is late 2014. I remain co-owner and have a very limited technical and strategic role. I was responsible for all software development and system administration for Big Shiba. This consisted mostly of PHP/MySQL development on Linux servers. I also developed programs to handle background tasks like automatically posting to Twitter, Facebook, and similar services. Our local development environment was built with Vagrant and Chef, while our production servers were managed with Chef.

EDUCATION

University of Texas in Austin, TX Computer Science (unfinished degree)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance
- Certified Scrum Product Owner, Scrum Alliance
- Zend Certified PHP 5.5 Engineer

SKILLS

- $\bullet \ Javascript/NodeJS/ReactJS$
- Agile methodologies (Scrum, Kanban, Scrum master, Product owner)
- AWS (including EC2, RDS, ELB, Lambda, Elasticache, Route 53, and many more)
- PHP (used <u>The Right Way</u> and frequently with Symfony)
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Mongo
- Git/GitHub/Bitbucket
- Software Testing/TDD (PHPUnit, Jasmine, Enzyme, Codeception) and Continuous Integration